ALEXANDRA HUFFMAN

Digital Designer

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alxhuff

Website: alexhuffmandigitaldesign.com

PROFILE

I am a Digital Designer with 2 years of experience in advertising and game production respectively. I created and implemented an in-house html banner production pipeline during my first month as an intern at On Ideas. Over the course of a year, I worked closely with the Digital Design Director to further optimize the pipeline. This work contributed to a campaign seeing double-digit percentage increases in conversions and revenue, and a 25% increase in conversions. In graduate school, I worked as lead animator on a team of 20 artists, programmers, and producers to develop an 8 month thesis game, which won an award at the Game Developers Conference of 2019 in San Francisco. Core competencies include motion graphics, keyframe animation, prototyping, and wireframing, and I am currently working on my Front-End React Development certification with SheCodes.

SOFTWARE

- Illustrator
- After Effects
- Photoshop
- InVision
- Google Web
- Maya
- Designer
- Unreal Engine 4
- InDesign

SKILLS

- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Keyframe
 Animation
- Motion Graphics
- CSS/HTML/JS

LANGUAGES

- English
- Spanish (fully bilingual)

EXPERIENCE

Junior Art Director | On Ideas Inc.

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020

- Refined the in-house html pipeline alongside the Digital Design
 Director, wireframing, designing, A/B testing, and developing html ads
 for several campaigns.
- Animated a TV spot and the display banners for a pro-bono campaign against hunger, which later won a gold ADDY award and succeeded in having over 8,000 meals donated to the hungry in Sarasota County.
- Created social media and display banner ads for a \$500,000 spring campaign while navigating the Covid-19 pandemic.

Design Intern | On Ideas Inc.

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

- Researched and implemented an in-house html pipeline, which had previously been outsourced, thereby expanding the agency's digital capabilities.
- Applied these skills to a National Awareness campaign for a kickboxing franchise that later won a silver ADDY award and saw a 25% increase in conversions compared to the previous year.

UI Designer | Suspicious Box, LLC

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

- Designed UI assets and helped mediate redesign midway through production.
- Storyboarded and directed opening trailer.
- Gathered data during testing to iterate and improve user experience.

EDUCATION

M.S. Interactive Entertainment | University of Central Florida

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

- Gained hands-on practice designing user experience, data collection, playtesting, and creating rapid prototypes (digital and paper).
- Created motion graphics, interactive animations, and UI assets.

B.A. English | University of North Florida

Aug 2011 - May 2014

- Minored in Psychology. Demonstrated aptitude in statistics and research methods coursework.
- Developed strong professional communication writing and research skills.